<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>is4tomj</title>
    <link>http://is4tomj.com/categories/private-pair/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on is4tomj</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <copyright>Tom Johnson</copyright>
    <atom:link href="http://is4tomj.com/categories/private-pair/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Patent Drafting: Detailed and Broad</title>
      <link>http://is4tomj.com/posts/0005-specificity-vs-breadth/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://is4tomj.com/posts/0005-specificity-vs-breadth/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A patent specification should be as detailed as possible, including as many specific examples and embodiments as possible. However, the claims in the patent should be as broad as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of my biggest pet-peeves is when a patent practitioner that should have a kung-fu-like grip on this topic says something like following, referring to drafting patents:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Attorneys are taught the art of both being hyper-specific, which is necessary at times, but also the art of being anything but specific. I would not say vague because a patent cannot be vague.&amp;rdquo; &amp;ndash; Gene Quinn &lt;a href=&#34;IPWatchDog.com&#34;&gt;IPWatchDog.com&lt;/a&gt; via this Inc. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.inc.com/stephen-key/should-you-hire-a-patent-agent-instead-of-a-patent-attorney.html&#34;&gt;post&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This statement confuses and frustrates the lay person. I am sure Gene Quinn understands this topic well, but for whatever reason, his statement was confusing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be clear: Nothing in a patent should be vague—ever. The claims should be broad, definite, and clear (&lt;a href=&#34;posts/sab-intro&#34;&gt;see Strict Antecedent Basis&lt;/a&gt;), but never vague. The specification should also be clear with as many embodiments with concrete examples as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Register and use a New Customer Number with the USPTO</title>
      <link>http://is4tomj.com/posts/0001-customer-number/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://is4tomj.com/posts/0001-customer-number/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m not going to go into why registering a customer number is important. I’m only going show the fastest way to create one and when to use it:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Go to Private Pair;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Search in the page for “PAIR Administration” and expand that region;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Select “Create New Customer Number” and “Continue”;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fill out the form;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Select “Preview”; and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Select “Submit”.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although the status will show “Submitted”, I was able to start using the new Customer Number right away. I was also able to edit my the Customer Number to add another attorney’s registration number.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>