<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>is4tomj</title>
    <link>http://is4tomj.com/categories/poa/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on is4tomj</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <copyright>Tom Johnson</copyright>
    <atom:link href="http://is4tomj.com/categories/poa/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Transfer representation for a case before the USPTO to a different agent or attorney for an application filed on or after September 16, 2012</title>
      <link>http://is4tomj.com/posts/0002%20-%20transfer-cases/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://is4tomj.com/posts/0002%20-%20transfer-cases/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;How you transfer a case depends on whether the case is a pending application, an issued patent, or a PCT Application. Each of these cases is discussed below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;transferring-a-pending-applications-or-provisional-applications-pending-or-expired&#34;&gt;Transferring a Pending Applications or Provisional Applications (pending or expired)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a pending U.S. Patent Application or a provisional application (pending or expired), filed on or after September 16, 2012, where the assignee-applicant was named as the applicant when the application was filed, use &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.uspto.gov/sites/default/files/forms/aia0082.pdf&#34;&gt;this form (PTO/AIA/82)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This form has Parts A, B, and C. Part C is only useful if the transferring attorney is not using a customer number, so I&amp;rsquo;m going to ignore Part C.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Part A has fields that identify the application being transferred and includes application specific data, such as an Application Number. Accordingly, Part A is different for each patent application you are transferring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Part B identifies the assignee-applicant and requires the client&amp;rsquo;s signature. A client can sign Part B once, and a copy of Part B can be attached to a copy of Part A for each patent application.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;transferring-an-issued-application&#34;&gt;Transferring an Issued Application&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For an issued U.S. Patent, filed on or after September 16, 2012, you must file two forms: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.uspto.gov/sites/default/files/documents/aia0081a.pdf&#34;&gt;POA for issued patents (PTO/AIA/81a)&lt;/a&gt; and a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.uspto.gov/sites/default/files/forms/aia0096.pdf&#34;&gt;37 CRF 3.73(c) Statement (PTO/AIA/96)&lt;/a&gt; Statement.  If a 37 CRF 3.73(c) Statement has already been filed, then you can simply identify the 3.73(c) Statement; otherwise, a 3.73(c) Statement can be drafted and filed with the POA.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;transferring-a-pct-application&#34;&gt;Transferring a PCT Application&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Appointment of an agent for a PCT, filed on or after September 16, 2012, may be effected by referring, in a request, demand, or separate notice, to an existing separate POA appointing that agent to represent the applicant. See &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.uspto.gov/web/offices/pac/mpep/mpep-9025-appx-t.html#d0e377280&#34;&gt;MPEP 9025&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am planning to file a POA using &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.uspto.gov/sites/default/files/forms/aia0080.pdf&#34;&gt;PTO/AIA/80&lt;/a&gt; with Parts A and B, which are the same parts that were used to transfer a pending application.  I will also file&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;notes&#34;&gt;Notes&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.uspto.gov/web/offices/pac/mpep/s402.html&#34;&gt;MPEP 402&lt;/a&gt; discusses Power of Attorney and naming a representative.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.uspto.gov/web/offices/pac/mpep/s1808.html&#34;&gt;MPEP 1808&lt;/a&gt; Change in or Revocation of the Appointment of an Agent or a Common Representative.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.uspto.gov/patent/forms/forms-patent-applications-filed-or-after-september-16-2012&#34;&gt;This is a list of forms that can be used to file or prosecute U.S. patent applications filed after September 16, 2012&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>