<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>is4tomj</title>
    <link>http://is4tomj.com/categories/strict-antecedent-basis/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on is4tomj</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <copyright>Tom Johnson</copyright>
    <atom:link href="http://is4tomj.com/categories/strict-antecedent-basis/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Strict Antecedent Basis: Sets and Iteration</title>
      <link>http://is4tomj.com/posts/sab-sets-and-iteration</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://is4tomj.com/posts/sab-sets-and-iteration</guid>
      <description>

&lt;hr/&gt;
I am updating, or adding to, this page. Please let me know if you have suggestions or fixes. You can let me know on &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/is4tomj&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Twitter (@is4tomj)&lt;/a&gt; or make a pull request on &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/is4tomj/is4tomj-hugo&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://github.com/is4tomj/is4tomj-hugo&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;sets&#34;&gt;Sets&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Attention&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: courts may construe a &amp;ldquo;set&amp;rdquo; of objects as two or more objects. Construing sets to mean two or more is a ridiculous interpretation because one skilled in the art of software knows that a set can comprise zero or more objects. One solution is to include the following in the specification:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A &amp;ldquo;set&amp;rdquo; may comprise zero, one, or two or more elements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-first-rule-of-sets-do-not-use-sets&#34;&gt;The first rule of sets — do not use sets&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sets often create confusion. Do not use a set unless a set is required.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In many cases, you can use one or two objects rather than a set. Referencing multiple references for multiple objects is usually clearer and broader than using sets. The following is an example:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-claim&#34;&gt;doing a first thing with a first object;
doing the first thing with a second object;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;second-rule-of-sets-if-using-a-set-is-required-then-do-not-use-respectively-language&#34;&gt;Second rule of sets – if using a set is required, then do not use &amp;ldquo;respectively&amp;rdquo; language&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A claim that uses a set often uses &amp;ldquo;respectively&amp;rdquo; haphazardly, and often incorrectly, throughout the claim. If two sets are needed, and each object in a first set is related to a corresponding object in a second set, then consider doing the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-claims&#34;&gt;A method comprising:
  ... a first set of objects;
  ... a second set of objects;
  wherein each object in the first set of objects has a corresponding object in the second set of objects;
  ...
  selecting a particular object from the first set of objects;
  ...
  performing a step with the particular object and the corresponding object.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;iterative-blocks&#34;&gt;Iterative blocks&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Iterating over a plurality of things leads to tricky claim language. When iterating over a set is required, perform the iteration with an iterative block. The following is an example of an iterative block that performs two actions on each object in a set:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-claim&#34;&gt;for each thing among a plurality of things:
  doing a first action with the thing;
  doing a second action with the thing;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this example, the claim is iterating over a set—the plurality of things— and doing a first action and a second action with the thing from the plurality of things in the current iteration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An iterative block may be a single line. For example, the following is an example of an iterative block that is a single line. The scope, which is discussed further herein, is just the single line.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-claim&#34;&gt;for each thing among a plurality of things, doing an action with the thing; 
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;scope-and-iterative-blocks&#34;&gt;Scope and iterative blocks&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The keyword phrase &lt;code&gt;each&lt;/code&gt;, unlike any of the other keyword phrases that instantiate a noun phrase, instantiates a noun phrase for an object only within the scope of the iterative block.  The following is an example that violates this rule.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-claim&#34;&gt;for each thing among a plurality of things:
  doing a first action with the thing; and
  doing a second action with the thing;
creating a particular widget;
doing a third action with the thing and the particular widget;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As seen in the example above, the reference to the thing in the last line is nonsensical, because the reference to the thing in the last line is outside the scope of the iterative block.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;multiple-iterative-blocks&#34;&gt;Multiple iterative blocks&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;nested-blocks&#34;&gt;Nested blocks&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Strict Antecedent Basis: Blocks and Scope</title>
      <link>http://is4tomj.com/posts/sab-blocks</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://is4tomj.com/posts/sab-blocks</guid>
      <description>

&lt;hr/&gt;
I am updating, or adding to, this page. Please let me know if you have suggestions or fixes. You can let me know on &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/is4tomj&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Twitter (@is4tomj)&lt;/a&gt; or make a pull request on &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/is4tomj/is4tomj-hugo&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://github.com/is4tomj/is4tomj-hugo&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;blocks&#34;&gt;Blocks&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A block is a group of components or steps that are related. Block that are multi-line blocks should be visually identifiable with indentation. The first line of a  multi-line block should end with a &lt;code&gt;:&lt;/code&gt; and each subsequent line in the block should have a deeper indentation than the first line of the block. The second to last line should end with one of the following, whichever is more appropriate:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;, or&lt;/code&gt;,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;; or&lt;/code&gt;,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;, and&lt;/code&gt;, or&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;; and&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following is an example of a  multi-line block.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-claim&#34;&gt;for each thing among a plurality of things:
  doing a first action with the thing; and
  doing a second action with the thing;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A single-line block is used primarily to iterate over a set. Accordingly, single-line blocks are discussed in &lt;a href=&#34;http://is4tomj.com/posts/sab-sets-and-iteration&#34;&gt;Sets and Iteration&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;nested-blocks&#34;&gt;Nested Blocks&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A block may include one or more blocks.  The following is an example of a block that includes a nested block.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-claim&#34;&gt;A method comprising:
  receiving a plurality of things;
  for each thing in the plurality of things:
    doing a first action with the thing; and
    doing a second action with the thing.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Strict Antecedent Basis: Noun Phrases</title>
      <link>http://is4tomj.com/posts/sab-noun-phrases</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://is4tomj.com/posts/sab-noun-phrases</guid>
      <description>

&lt;hr/&gt;
I am updating, or adding to, this page. Please let me know if you have suggestions or fixes. You can let me know on &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/is4tomj&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Twitter (@is4tomj)&lt;/a&gt; or make a pull request on &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/is4tomj/is4tomj-hugo&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://github.com/is4tomj/is4tomj-hugo&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;noun-phrases-the-building-blocks-of-clear-claim-language&#34;&gt;Noun phrases &amp;ndash; the building blocks of clear claim language&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A noun phrase is a word or group of words that functions in a sentence as subject, object, or prepositional object. A noun phrase in a claim should be clearly defined so that future references to the noun phrase are easily recognized.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;instantiating-a-noun-phrase&#34;&gt;Instantiating a noun phrase&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A noun phrase should be instantiated only once in a claim using one keyword phrase among a set of instantiating keyword phrases:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;a&lt;/code&gt;,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;an&lt;/code&gt;,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;one|two|&lt;/code&gt;,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;at least&lt;/code&gt;,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;each&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following are examples of instantiating a noun phrase with a keyword phrase from the set of instantiating keyword phrases:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;a first thing&lt;/code&gt;,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;a second thing&lt;/code&gt;,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;a plurality of things&lt;/code&gt;,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;one or more things&lt;/code&gt;,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;two or more things&lt;/code&gt;,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;three or more things&lt;/code&gt;,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;at least one thing&lt;/code&gt;,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;at least two things&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;each&lt;/code&gt; instantiating keyword phrase is a special keyword phrase that is discussed in &lt;a href=&#34;http://is4tomj.com/posts/sab-sets-and-iteration&#34;&gt;Sets and Iteration&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;referring-to-an-instantiated-noun-phrase&#34;&gt;Referring to an instantiated noun phrase&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Use the &lt;code&gt;the&lt;/code&gt; keyword phrase to reference a noun phrase exactly as instantiated. The following are examples of referencing an instantiated noun phrase:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;the first thing&lt;/code&gt;,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;the second thing&lt;/code&gt;,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;the plurality of things&lt;/code&gt;,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;the one or more things&lt;/code&gt;,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;the two or more things&lt;/code&gt;,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;the three or more things&lt;/code&gt;,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;the at least one thing&lt;/code&gt;,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;the at least two things&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A noun phrase should not be referenced using a modifier, such as an adjective.  For example, if a claim includes &lt;code&gt;receiving a thing&lt;/code&gt;, then &lt;code&gt;the thing&lt;/code&gt; should &lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; be referenced as &lt;code&gt;the received thing&lt;/code&gt; in the claim.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;a-noun-phrase-references-an-immutable-object&#34;&gt;A noun phrase references an immutable object&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A noun phrase references an object that is immutable. If the object is modified, then the object is a new object.  Accordingly, a new noun phrase should be instantiated to represent the new object.  The following is an example of assigning a new noun phrase to a modified object:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-claim&#34;&gt;1. A method comprising:
   receiving a first thing;
   modifying the first thing to produce a second thing.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do not make a noun phrase ambiguous by referring to two objects with the same noun phrase.  The following is an example of a claim that creates an antecedent basis error by using a single noun phrase to reference two objects with different states:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-claim&#34;&gt;1. A method comprising:
   receiving a thing that includes an original component;
   modifying the original component included in the thing;
   sending the thing to a client computer.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some may argue that sending &lt;code&gt;the thing&lt;/code&gt; clearly means sending &lt;code&gt;the thing&lt;/code&gt; with a new component from a previous component included in &lt;code&gt;the claim&lt;/code&gt;. However, that logic requires steps in a claim to have a rigid order, and someone could invent around the claimed invention by merely performing two or more steps in a different order. Furthermore, in a long or subsequent dependent claim, a reader may also have a hard time determining whether a reference to &lt;code&gt;the thing&lt;/code&gt; is referring to &lt;code&gt;the thing&lt;/code&gt; with the previous component or the new component.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following claim is free of antecedent basis errors by assigning a new noun phrase to a new object created by modifying an original object:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-claim&#34;&gt;1. A method comprising:
   receiving a first thing that includes a particular component;
   producing a second thing from the first thing by modifying the particular component;
   sending the second thing to a client computer.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;do-not-instantiate-a-new-noun-phrase-for-further-characterization-clarification-or-description-of-an-underlying-component&#34;&gt;Do not instantiate a new noun phrase for further characterization, clarification, or description of an underlying component.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although a noun phrase represents an immutable object, a new noun phrase should not be instantiated when an object is merely further characterized, clarified, or described.  The following is an example of a noun phrase that represents an object that is further described after the noun phrase was instantiated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-claim&#34;&gt;1. A method comprising:
   receiving a thing, wherein the thing has a particular component;
   sending the thing to a client computer.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Strict Antecedent Basis: Introduction</title>
      <link>http://is4tomj.com/posts/sab-intro</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://is4tomj.com/posts/sab-intro</guid>
      <description>

&lt;hr/&gt;
I am updating, or adding to, this page. Please let me know if you have suggestions or fixes. You can let me know on &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/is4tomj&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Twitter (@is4tomj)&lt;/a&gt; or make a pull request on &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/is4tomj/is4tomj-hugo&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://github.com/is4tomj/is4tomj-hugo&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;strict-antecedent-basis&#34;&gt;Strict Antecedent Basis&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;It is of utmost importance that patents issue with definite claims that clearly and precisely inform persons skilled in the art of the boundaries of protected subject matter.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.uspto.gov/web/offices/pac/mpep/s2173.html&#34;&gt;MPEP 2173&lt;/a&gt;; see 35 U.S.C § 112(b). Unfortunately, the English language is too flexible and too complicated for many people to write a clear claim.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Strict Antecedent Basis is a standard that eliminates many ambiguities. Strict Antecedent Basis rules are tailored to draft claims that clearly meet the standards of the USPTO and US law. A claim may still be valid and clear without adhering to Strict Antecedent Basis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Definite claims do not mean narrow claims, and indefinite or ambiguous claims do not mean broad claims. A good patent practitioner drafts claims that are both definite and broad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A court can just as easily construe an ambiguous term narrowly instead of broadly. I would prefer to stand confidently in court knowing that an infringer is clearly infringing my patent rather than hoping that I fall ass-backwards into good fortune with a court that construes my claims broadly enough for me stop, or collect a royalty from, the infringer. Furthermore, requiring a court to construe ambiguous claims can increase the cost of litigation or worse &amp;ndash; invalidate my patent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following posts define the Strict Antecedent Basis rules and provide numerous examples. I will update posts and add new posts over time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
  
  
    
  
    
  
    
  
    
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://is4tomj.com/posts/sab-intro&#34;&gt;Strict Antecedent Basis: Introduction&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    
  
    
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://is4tomj.com/posts/sab-noun-phrases&#34;&gt;Strict Antecedent Basis: Noun Phrases&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    
  
    
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://is4tomj.com/posts/sab-blocks&#34;&gt;Strict Antecedent Basis: Blocks and Scope&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    
  
    
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://is4tomj.com/posts/sab-sets-and-iteration&#34;&gt;Strict Antecedent Basis: Sets and Iteration&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    
  
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>