<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>is4tomj</title>
    <link>http://is4tomj.com/categories/transfer-cases/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on is4tomj</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <copyright>Tom Johnson</copyright>
    <atom:link href="http://is4tomj.com/categories/transfer-cases/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Transfer representation for a case before the USPTO to a different agent or attorney</title>
      <link>http://is4tomj.com/posts/transfer-cases/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://is4tomj.com/posts/transfer-cases/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;How you transfer a case depends on whether the case is a pending application, an issued patent, or a PCT Application. Each of these cases is discussed below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;transferring-a-pending-application&#34;&gt;Transferring a Pending Application&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a pending U.S. Patent Application where the assignee-applicant was named as the applicant when the application was filed, use &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.uspto.gov/sites/default/files/forms/aia0082.pdf&#34;&gt;this form&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This form has Parts A, B, and C. Part C is only useful if there is not customer number, so I&amp;rsquo;m going to ignore Part C.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Part A has fields that identify the application being transferred and includes application specific data, such as an Application Number and Confirmation Number. Accordingly, Part A is different for each patent application you are transferring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Part B identifies the assignee-applicant and requires the client&amp;rsquo;s signature. A client can sign Part B once, and a copy of Part B can be attached to a copy of Part A for each patent application.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;transferring-an-issued-application&#34;&gt;Transferring an Issued Application&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For an issued U.S. Patent, use the following form: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.uspto.gov/sites/default/files/documents/aia0081a.pdf&#34;&gt;Power of Attorney or Revocation of Power of Attorney With a New Power of Attorney and Change of Correspondence Address&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;transferring-a-pct-application&#34;&gt;Transferring a PCT Application&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(TODO: update after transferring a PCT case.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;notes&#34;&gt;Notes&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.uspto.gov/web/offices/pac/mpep/s402.html&#34;&gt;MPEP 402&lt;/a&gt; discusses Power of Attorney and naming a representative.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.uspto.gov/patent/forms/forms-patent-applications-filed-or-after-september-16-2012&#34;&gt;This is a list of forms that can be used to file or prosecute U.S. patent applications filed after September 16, 2012&lt;/a&gt;, which includes &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.uspto.gov/sites/default/files/documents/aia0081a.pdf&#34;&gt;Power of Attorney or Revocation of Power of Attorney With a New Power of Attorney and Change of Correspondence Address&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>