<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts-rsses on is4tomj</title>
    <link>http://is4tomj.com/posts/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts-rsses on is4tomj</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <copyright>Tom Johnson</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://is4tomj.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Properties of a Well-Written Draft Patent Application</title>
      <link>http://is4tomj.com/posts/0003%20-%20drafting-patent-applications/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://is4tomj.com/posts/0003%20-%20drafting-patent-applications/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;qualities-of-a-well-written-draft-patent-application&#34;&gt;Qualities of a well-written draft patent application&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A draft patent application should be easy for an inventor (and everyone else) to read.  A well-written specification includes lots of headings and subheadings, is written in active voice as much as possible, avoids pronouns, avoids jargon, uses terms consistently, fully supports the claims.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;background-section-and-first-substantive-section-after-the-background&#34;&gt;Background section and first substantive section after the background&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The background of a draft patent application should describe the problem that the invention solves. The first substantive section after the background, should summarize the solution.  Headings should then allow a reader to jump to specific sections that discuss specific components or steps.  Adding a table of contents before the General Overview section is strongly encouraged.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;boilerplate-language&#34;&gt;Boilerplate language&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Boilerplate language about basic computer components or topologies should be grouped together. The meat of the draft patent application should be highlighted so that the inventors know what to focus on while reviewing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;dont-s&#34;&gt;Dont&amp;rsquo;s:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please do not use any of the following in a draft patent application:
- &amp;ldquo;e.g.&amp;rdquo;: use &amp;ldquo;for example&amp;rdquo;;
- &amp;ldquo;i.e.&amp;rdquo;;
- Pronouns;
- Patent profanity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;summary-section&#34;&gt;Summary Section&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please do not include a Summary section that states anything other than the following: “The appended claims may serve as a summary of the invention.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;claims&#34;&gt;Claims&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Claims should adhere to Strict Antecedent Basis Rules. For example, “the &amp;lt;something&amp;gt;” should only occur after “a &amp;lt;something&amp;gt;”.  I will have a separate post that defines Strict Antecedent Basis Rules with several examples.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transfer representation for a case before the USPTO to a different agent or attorney for an application filed on or after September 16, 2012</title>
      <link>http://is4tomj.com/posts/0002%20-%20transfer-cases/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://is4tomj.com/posts/0002%20-%20transfer-cases/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;How you transfer a case depends on whether the case is a pending application, an issued patent, or a PCT Application. Each of these cases is discussed below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;transferring-a-pending-applications-or-provisional-applications-pending-or-expired&#34;&gt;Transferring a Pending Applications or Provisional Applications (pending or expired)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a pending U.S. Patent Application or a provisional application (pending or expired), filed on or after September 16, 2012, where the assignee-applicant was named as the applicant when the application was filed, use &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.uspto.gov/sites/default/files/forms/aia0082.pdf&#34;&gt;this form (PTO/AIA/82)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This form has Parts A, B, and C. Part C is only useful if the transferring attorney is not using a customer number, so I&amp;rsquo;m going to ignore Part C.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Part A has fields that identify the application being transferred and includes application specific data, such as an Application Number. Accordingly, Part A is different for each patent application you are transferring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Part B identifies the assignee-applicant and requires the client&amp;rsquo;s signature. A client can sign Part B once, and a copy of Part B can be attached to a copy of Part A for each patent application.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;transferring-an-issued-application&#34;&gt;Transferring an Issued Application&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For an issued U.S. Patent, filed on or after September 16, 2012, you must file two forms: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.uspto.gov/sites/default/files/documents/aia0081a.pdf&#34;&gt;POA for issued patents (PTO/AIA/81a)&lt;/a&gt; and a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.uspto.gov/sites/default/files/forms/aia0096.pdf&#34;&gt;37 CRF 3.73(c) Statement (PTO/AIA/96)&lt;/a&gt; Statement.  If a 37 CRF 3.73(c) Statement has already been filed, then you can simply identify the 3.73(c) Statement; otherwise, a 3.73(c) Statement can be drafted and filed with the POA.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;transferring-a-pct-application&#34;&gt;Transferring a PCT Application&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Appointment of an agent for a PCT, filed on or after September 16, 2012, may be effected by referring, in a request, demand, or separate notice, to an existing separate POA appointing that agent to represent the applicant. See &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.uspto.gov/web/offices/pac/mpep/mpep-9025-appx-t.html#d0e377280&#34;&gt;MPEP 9025&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am planning to file a POA using &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.uspto.gov/sites/default/files/forms/aia0080.pdf&#34;&gt;PTO/AIA/80&lt;/a&gt; with Parts A and B, which are the same parts that were used to transfer a pending application.  I will also file&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;notes&#34;&gt;Notes&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.uspto.gov/web/offices/pac/mpep/s402.html&#34;&gt;MPEP 402&lt;/a&gt; discusses Power of Attorney and naming a representative.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.uspto.gov/web/offices/pac/mpep/s1808.html&#34;&gt;MPEP 1808&lt;/a&gt; Change in or Revocation of the Appointment of an Agent or a Common Representative.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.uspto.gov/patent/forms/forms-patent-applications-filed-or-after-september-16-2012&#34;&gt;This is a list of forms that can be used to file or prosecute U.S. patent applications filed after September 16, 2012&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Register and use a New Customer Number with the USPTO</title>
      <link>http://is4tomj.com/posts/0001%20-%20customer-number/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://is4tomj.com/posts/0001%20-%20customer-number/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m not going to go into why registering a customer number is important. I’m only going show the fastest way to create one and when to use it:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Go to Private Pair;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Search in the page for “PAIR Administration” and expand that region;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Select “Create New Customer Number” and “Continue”;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fill out the form;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Select “Preview”; and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Select “Submit”.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although the status will show “Submitted”, I was able to start using the new Customer Number right away. I was also able to edit my the Customer Number to add another attorney’s registration number.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>